Arthur Jacobs | Curriculum Vitae

Travessa da Paz #26, Apt. 202, 90040-100 - Porto Alegre, RS - Brazil

✓ asjacobs@inf.ufrgs.br • ♦ https://asjacobs92.github.io/Male, Brazilian citizen, born on 10/Sep/1992.

First year PhD student in Computer Science, in the Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul. Passionate about science and development, with strong will to learn about a multitude of subjects, and to build impacting and complex projects. Research interests include network management, Network Functions Virtualization, self-driving networks, programmable networks and artificial intelligence.

Education

PhD in Computer Science

Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul

Study Abroad, Brazil Scientific Mobility Program

University of Maryland

BSc in Computer Science

• Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul

August 2017 – June 2021 (Expected)
Porto Alegre, RS — Brazil

January 2014 – December 2014 College Park, MD — US

March 2011 - December 2016

Porto Alegre, RS — Brazil

Research Experience

Doctoral Researcher

August 2017 - Current

Networks Lab, Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul

Porto Alegre, RS — Brazil

- Worked under the supervision of Prof. Lisandro Z. Granville, researching network management topics, such as Network Functions Virtualization and Software Defined Networking.
- Developed an affinity metric for Virtualized Network Functions, to identify and prevent performance degradations and resource contention in virtualized Service Function Chains.
- Studied the use of artificial intelligence techniques, such as neural networks, to prevent misconfiguration of Virtualized Network Functions, based on the proposed affinity metric.

Undergraduate Researcher

August 2012 - May 2013

Networks Lab, Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul

- Porto Alegre, RS Brazil
- Worked under the supervision of, then, PhD student Cristiano B. Both, in a joint project with company Datacom Inc., researching on using artificial intelligence to generate alarms for network operators.
- Developed monitoring web platform using Java, and the Vaadin web framework.
- Worked in a four-member team using agile methodology Scrum.

Undergraduate Researcher

August 2011 - August 2012

Networks Lab, Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul

Porto Alegre, RS — Brazil

- Worked under the supervision of, then, PhD student Oscar M. Caicedo, researching on management on virtualized network using Mashup applications.
- Investigated network virtualization background and related works on the research topic.
- Built virtualized network testbed using Xen and Virtual Box, and aided in development of Javascript Mashup monitoring application.

Employment History

Software Developer

May 2016 - September 2017

ADP, LLC.

Porto Alegre, RS — Brazil

- Acted as Software Architect on agile Discovery Teams, alongside a Development Leader and a Senior Product Owner, carrying out a leadership position in the development process.
- Worked with several different Scrum teams, supporting the development of architected solutions, both in Progress 4GL and Java.
- Worked closely with infrastructure teams, both in Brazil and Chile, to configure and manage execution environments of developed applications.

Software Developer Intern

September 2015 - May 2016

ADP, LLC.

Porto Alegre, RS — Brazil

- Developed Java application to deploy ADP's database information for the government project eSocial, using Spring and SOAP web services.
- Developed a web portal to monitor the deployment application's health.
- Worked in a three-member team using agile methodology Scrum.

Software Developer Intern

May 2014 - August 2014

College Park, MD — US

- HCI Labs, University of Maryland
 - Worked under the supervision of Prof. Mark Jacobs, in the Human-Computer Interactions labs of University
 of Maryland.
 - Developed Android version of the iOS app, Leafsnap, to identify trees and plants based on photos of leaves.
 - Ported the Objective-C APIs, used in Leafsnap for iOS, to Java.

Research Publications

Peer-Reviewed Conference Papers.....

- o <u>A. S. Jacobs</u>, R. J. Pfitscher, R. L. dos Santos, M. F. Franco, E. J. Scheid and L. Z. Granville, "Artificial Neural Network Model to Predict Affinity for Virtual Network Functions", In *2018 IFIP/IEEE Network Operations and Management Symposium (NOMS)*, **To appear**, Taipei, Taiwan (2018).
- R. J. Pfitscher, E. J. Scheid, <u>A. S. Jacobs</u>, M. F. Franco, R. L. dos Santos, A. E. Schaeffer-Filho and L. Z. Granville, "A Model for Quantifying Performance Degradation in Virtual Network Function Service Chains", In 2018 IFIP/IEEE Network Operations and Management Symposium (NOMS), To appear, Taipei, Taiwan (2018).
- A. S. Jacobs, R. L. dos Santos, M. F. Franco, E. J. Scheid, R. J. Pfitscher and L. Z. Granville, "Affinity measurement for NFV-enabled networks: A criteria-based approach", In 2017 IFIP/IEEE Symposium on Integrated Network and Service Management (IM), pages 125-133, Lisbon, Portugal (2017).

Peer-reviewed Journal Articles.....

o O. M. C. Rendon, C. R. P. dos Santos, <u>A. S. Jacobs</u> and L. Z. Granville, "Monitoring Virtual Nodes using mashups", In *Computer Networks*, Volume 64, pages 55 - 70 (2014).

Posters, Workshops and Others....

A. S. Jacobs, R. L. dos Santos, M. F. Franco, E. J. Scheid, R. J. Pfitscher, L. Z. Granville, "AMNESiA: Affinity measurement platform for NFV-enabled networks", In 2017 IFIP/IEEE Symposium on Integrated Network and Service Management (IM), pages 899-900, Lisbon, Portugal (2017).

Technical skills

- Programming Languages: C, C++, C#, Java, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Python, OCaml, Progress 4GL and SQL.
- Tools and Frameworks: Git, SVN and Mercurial; Hibernate and ORMLite; Maven and Gradle; Spring; Bootstrap, JQuery and Underscore; Node.js, AngularJS, Ionic and Django.
- **Databases:** Firebase, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Oracle and Progress.

Reference

- Lisandro Zambenedetti Granville
- Assoc. Professor of Computer Science
- im Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul

Language skills

- Portuguese: native.
- **English:** fluent.
- Spanish: advanced.
- **German:** basic.